<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Mousefolk</name>
		<description></description>
		<author url="https://www.dandwiki.com/wiki/Mousefolk_(5e_Race)">DnD Wiki</author>
		<update version="0.1.6">
			<file name="mousefolk.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/core/players-handbook/races/race-halfling.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Mousefolk" type="Race" source="Ryan" id="ID_RACE_MOUSEFOLK">
		<description>
			<p class="flavor">The life of the Mousefolk is one spent close to the ground. With no great empires or kingdoms to call home, the Mousefolk spend their lives carving a place for themselves in the cities of the larger races or in the untamed wilds. They form tight-knit communities where every member is expected to contribute to the success of the whole. Some Mousefolk study a trade skill to support their families, while others use their natural agility and intellect for contract services.</p>

			<h4>PHYSICAL DESCRIPTION</h4>
			<p>Reaching a little over 2 foot tall, the Mousefolk often go unnoticed in their day to day activities. Their diminutive stature and quiet demeanor make the Mousefolk inoffensive to most, granting a certain detachment from the major conflicts and strife of the age. Their fast metabolisms and quick feet give the Mousefolk a slender build, usually weighing around 25 pounds.</p>
			<p class="indent">Mousefolk fur color ranges from white to tan to brown or black, with various patterns passed through heredity. They take care to groom and clean their fur, as it represents their family and community. A Mousefolk's eye color is either red or black. Mousefolk like to wear comfortable dark colored clothes that allow for discretion and a wide range of movement.</p>
			<p class="indent">The concept of personal wealth or glory doesn’t pervade through Mousefolk culture, most actions taken are for the good of the community rather than the self. Any wealth or resources gained are utilized for the betterment of the group. Some Mousefolk, however, use their natural abilities for personal gain. These individuals tend to be outcasts or black sheep of the clans.</p>

			<h4>SOCIETY</h4>
			<p>The Mousefolk are a resourceful and tenacious race. Mousefolk settlements can be found in the most unlikely and inhospitable of places. They tend to build homes in the dark shadows and forgotten corners of the world, such as city slums, deep forests, scorching deserts, arctic tundra, or port cities in exotic lands. The Mousefolk aren't typically farmers, instead preferring hunting, trade, and craft to meet their needs. Mousefolk caravans are not an easy target for bandits, guarded by skilled archers within and a bristling wall of oak and steel without.</p>
			<p class="indent">Mousefolk families extend beyond blood ties, an individual's entire community is treated as kin. Mousefolk settlers will seek out other colonies, and new warrens will arise within close proximity to each other. These communities will eventually grow and merge the members of each becoming kin to the other.</p>

			<h4>MOUSEFOLK NAMES</h4>
			<p>When a Mousefolk is old enough to read, they are taken by an elder to the clan's archives to study the lore and histories of their people. After several years, the individual is allowed to pick their own name, either adopting the name of a past hero or inventing a new name for themselves.</p>
			<p>
				<span class="feature">Male Names:</span>Aengus, Ashwin, Aynselle, Boris, Byrnstan, Carius, Celanawe, Colin, Demitri, Elric, Esegar, Finn, Gregory, Joseph, Luke, Martin, Matthias, Mattimeo, Odric, Seyth, Thorn, Waldwin<br/>
				<span class="feature">Female Names:</span>Baeylie, Caley, Clove, Daewn, Dalla, Eda, Elis, Gale, Ingrid, Kearra, Marie!, Millicent, Moira, Nola, Rona, Rosalee, Sayble, Serra, Sylvia, Veira<br/>
				<span class="feature">Historical Names:</span>Abershaw, Bluebell, Dalgill, Faolan, Garrow, Gamilon, Grimwold, Hannidy, Larkin, Sloan, Taryn, Tenny, Tinble, Toller, Vidar, Walmond<br/>
			</p>

			<h4>MOUSEFOLK TRAITS</h4>
			<p>Mousefolk character has a number of traits in common with all other Mousefolk.</p>
			<p class="indent">Furry, nimble, small, retiring and agreeable race.</p>
			<p>
				<span class="feature">Ability Score Increase.</span>Your Dexterity score increases by 2.<br/>
				<span class="feature">Age.</span>A mousefolk reaches adulthood at the age of 5 and lives to be about 40 years old.<br/>
				<span class="feature">Alignment.</span>Most mousefolk are neutral and tend towards good. They try to keep the conflicts of the other races at arm's length but display remarkable ferocity when their friends, families, or communities are threatened. A reverence for nature and life is close to the heart of mousefolk, and they are loath to take a life if it can be avoided. They prefer to live quiet and unassuming lives, giving honest work for honest pay.<br/>
				<span class="feature">Size.</span>Mousefolk grow around 2 feet tall and weigh about 25 pounds. Your size is Small.<br/>
				<span class="feature">Speed.</span>Your base walking speed is 25 feet.<br/>
				<span class="feature">Keen Senses.</span>You have proficiency in the Perception skill.<br/>
				<span class="feature">Mousefolk Weapon Training.</span>You have proficiency with the rapier, shortsword, shortbow, and handaxe.<br/>
				<span class="feature">Nimble Dodge.</span>When attacked by an attack of opportunity, you may use your reaction to impose disadvantage on that attack.<br/>
				<span class="feature">Languages.</span>You can speak, read, and write Common and Squeak Speak. Squeak Speak can be used to speak with other rodents and uses the Sylvan script. Mousefolk place great value on the written accounts of their legends and histories and encourage everyone to keep journals and records of their deeds. Almost all Mousefolk speak Common to converse with the people on whose lands they dwell or through which they are traveling.<br/>
				<span class="feature">Subrace.</span>The two main kinds of Mousefolk, Softpaw and Meadowgard, are more like closely related families than true subraces. Choose one of these subraces.<br/>
			</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<setters>
			<set name="names" type="male">Aengus, Ashwin, Aynselle, Boris, Byrnstan, Carius, Celanawe, Colin, Demitri, Elric, Esegar, Finn, Gregory, Joseph, Luke, Martin, Matthias, Mattimeo, Odric, Seyth, Thorn, Waldwin</set>
			<set name="names" type="female">Baeylie, Caley, Clove, Daewn, Dalla, Eda, Elis, Gale, Ingrid, Kearra, Marie!, Millicent, Moira, Nola, Rona, Rosalee, Sayble, Serra, Sylvia, Veira</set>
			<set name="names-format">{{name}}</set>
			<set name="height" modifier="2d4">1'5"</set>
			<set name="weight" modifier="1d4">20 lb.</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="dexterity" value="2"/>
			<stat name="innate speed" value="25" bonus="base"/>
			<grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_SMALL" />
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" />
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_SQUEAK" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_KEEN_SENSES" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_MOUSE_WEAPON_TRAINING" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_MOUSE_NIMBLE_DODGE" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_MOUSE_SUBRACE" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Mousefolk Weapon Training" type="Racial Trait" source="Ryan" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_MOUSE_WEAPON_TRAINING">
		<description>
			<p>You have proficiency with the rapier, shortsword, shortbow, and handaxe.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>You have proficiency with the rapier, shortsword, shortbow, and handaxe.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_RAPIER" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SHORTSWORD" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SHORTBOW" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_HANDAXE" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Nimble Dodge" type="Racial Trait" source="Ryan" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_MOUSE_NIMBLE_DODGE">
		<description>
			<p>When attacked by an attack of opportunity, you may use your reaction to impose disadvantage on that attack.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When attacked by an attack of opportunity, you may use your reaction to impose disadvantage on that attack.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Mousefolk Subrace" type="Racial Trait" source="Ryan" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_MOUSE_SUBRACE">
		<description>
			<p>The two main kinds of Mousefolk, Softpaw and Meadowgard, are more like closely related families than true subraces. Choose one of these subraces.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Sub Race" name="Mousefolk Subrace" supports="Mousefolk" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Softpaw" type="Sub Race" source="Ryan" id="ID_SUB_RACE_SOFTPAW_MOUSEFOLK">
		<supports>Mousefolk</supports>
		<description>
			<p>
				<span class="feature">Ability Score Increase.</span>Your Intelligence score increases by 1.<br/>
				<span class="feature">Artistry.</span>You gain proficiency with one type of artisan's tools or one musical instrument.<br/>
				<span class="feature">Squirm.</span>You can move through Tiny sized spaces as if you were Tiny size.<br/>
			</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<stat name="intelligence" value="1" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_MOUSE_ARTISTRY" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_MOUSE_SQUIRM" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Artistry" type="Racial Trait" source="Ryan" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_MOUSE_ARTISTRY">
		<description>
			<p>You gain proficiency with one type of artisan's tools or one musical instrument.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You gain proficiency with one type of artisan's tools or one musical instrument.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Artistry" supports="Tool||Musical Instrument" />
		</rules>
	</element>	
	<element name="Squirm" type="Racial Trait" source="Ryan" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_MOUSE_SQUIRM">
		<description>
			<p>You can move through Tiny sized spaces as if you were Tiny size.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can move through Tiny sized spaces as if you were Tiny size.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Meadowgard" type="Sub Race" source="Ryan" id="ID_SUB_RACE_MEADOWGARD_MOUSEFOLK">
	<supports>Mousefolk</supports>
		<description>
			<p>
				<span class="feature">Ability Score Increase.</span>Your Wisdom score increases by 1.<br/>
				<span class="feature">Brave.</span>You have advantage on saving throws against being frightened.<br/>
				<span class="feature">Speak With Small Beasts.</span>Through sounds and gestures, you can communicate simple ideas with Small or smaller beasts.<br/>
			</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<stat name="wisdom" value="1" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_BRAVE" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_SPEAK_WITH_SMALL_BEASTS" />
		</rules>
	</element>
 
	<element name="Squeak Speak" type="Language" source="Ryan" id="ID_LANGUAGE_SQUEAK">
		<supports>Exotic</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Typically spoken by Mousefolk.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="exotic">true</set>
			<set name="speakers">Mousefolk</set>
			<set name="script">Sylvan</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
</elements>