<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Lingering Soul</name>
        <description>Lingering Soul.</description>
        <author url="https://img.fireden.net/tg/image/1511/28/1511285281092.pdf">Matthew Mercer</author>
        <update version="1.1">
            <file name="class-bloodhunter.xml" url="" />
        </update>
    </info>
    <element name="Lingering Soul" type="Class" source="Ryan" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_LINGERING_SOUL">
        <description>
            <p>Mortality. All who draw breath fear the icy grip of death, the promised end. It is the primal fear that drives much of his tory, and the promise of a restful afterlife brings weight to the in fl uence of any temple.</p>
            <p class="indent">Your afte rlife, unfortunately, is not so restful. You've been cut down, le ft to die, and your spirit now remains, unable to pass on when so fi lled with fear, with anger, with questions. Binding to whatever symbol will anchor you to the world of the living, you feel the hunger for answers rival your need for vengeance as you learn to control thi s e thereal exis tence thrust upon you.</p>
            <p class="indent">With the aid of s till-living allies, you continue the purs uit of your goals us ing your spectral gifts to frighten, manipulate, and control those who would stand in your way. Leaping from body to body, wr estling control from your foes as you send them to a worser fate than yours, you continue to fight for another chance at life ... or embrace your ghos tly talents to do what living mortals cannot, ever fighting the cold and hungry urges that encompass the curse of undeath.</p>
            <p class="indent"><i>This is a complicated class the DM can offer as a choice upon character creation, or offered by the DM when a player character death is surrounded by enough violence or myste1y to cause the soul to cling to the mortal world. It can allow the continued play of a beloved character when resurrection is unavailable, or as a reward for a party seeking to restore the narrative lost when a central figure has fallen. Players should not be able to select to become a Lingering Soul upon death; it should be offered with good reason, and it should be an option granted sparingly.</i></p>
			<h4>CREATING A LINGERING SOUL</h4>
            <p>As you step into the world of wandering spirits, be mindful of the circumstances that led to your demise. Fear or anger may forever be ingrained within you rega rding related places or people. Vengea nce drives those souls who met an unjust end at the hand of others, and your will may push you towards avenging what undue death found you. Others may remain to protect their friends as they reach a goa l, leaving you to guide them a long a hope you fell pursuing. What idea ls keep your soul in the world of the living?</p>
            <p class="indent">This can be a challenging class, both for the player, and the Dungeon Master. Being a Lingering Soul bestows the player with a number of very useful utility features, survival techniques, and a very unique way of addressing most any combat encounter. It also can a llow the continued play of a fallen character while magic to restore them is currently unavailable. However, many of these abili ties can lead to dangerous circumstances if ca re is not take n. They also suffer from lower hit points, a general lack of armor, and the threat of looming permanent death.</p>
			<p class="indent">As a note, Lingering Souls are unable to multiclass.</p>
            <h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
            <p>You can make a lingering soul quickly by following these suggestions. First, make Strength or Dexterity your highest ability score if you plan to develop into a Poltergeist. Alternatively, you could make Dexterity or Intelligence your highest ability score if you want to become a Wraith, or if becoming a Spiritual Guardian is your style, select Wisdom or Charisma. Next, invest in a higher Constitution, as healing and survival can prove tricky. Then, select the background that befits your life before death.</p>
            <h3>CLASS FEATURES</h3>
            <p>As a lingering soul, you gain the following class features.</p>
            <h5>HIT POINTS</h5>
            <p>
                <span class="emphasis">Hit Dice:</span>1d6 per lingering soul level
                <br />
                <span class="emphasis">Hit Points at 1st Level:</span>6 + your Constitution modifier
                <br />
                <span class="emphasis">Hit Points at Higher Levels:</span>1d6 (or 4) + your Constitution modifier per lingering soul level after 1st
            </p>
            <h5>PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <p>
                <span class="emphasis">Armor:</span>None 
                <br />
                <span class="emphasis">Weapons:</span>None
                <br />
                <span class="emphasis">Tools:</span>None
            </p>
            <p>
                <span class="emphasis">Saving Throws:</span>Constitution
                <br />
                <span class="emphasis">Skills:</span>Choose three skills from History, Investigation, Insight, Intimidation, Perception, Religion, S leight of Hand, or Stealth.
            </p>
            <h5>EQUIPMENT</h5>
            <p>You start with the following equipment yow- body would have on it, in addition to the equipment granted by your background, though carrying this equipment may prove difficult without aid.</p>
            <ul>
                <li>
                    <i>a simple weapon</i>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <i>(a) a dungeoneer's pack or (b) an explorer's pack</i> 
                </li>
                <li>
                    <i>a trinket (rolled on the Trinkets table, PHB pg.l60)</i>
                </li>
            </ul>
			<h5>TAKING OVER A DEAD CHARACTER</h5>
			<p>If a deceased player character returns as a Lingering Soul, they lose all previous class levels and abilities, instead returning with a number of levels in Lingering Soul equal to one less than their previous character level. They retain any languages they knew in life, as well as racial benefits and abilities, but lose all previous skill proficiencies, saving throw proficiencies, feats, and Ability Score improvements gained via class levels.</p>
            <div element="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_LINGERING_SOUL_SPIRIT_BINDING" />
            <div element="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_LINGERING_SOUL_PHANTOM_CALLING" />
            <div element="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_LINGERING_SOUL_GHOSTLY_FORM" />
			<div element="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_LINGERING_SOUL_POSSESSION" />
			<div element="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_LINGERING_SOUL_CONSUME_ENCHANTMENT" />
            <div element="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_ABILITYSCOREIMPROVEMENT_LINGERINGSPIRIT" />
			<div element="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_LINGERING_SOUL_PREVADE_THE_FALLEN" />
			<div element="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_LINGERING_SOUL_UNSEEN_PASSENGER" />
			<div element="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_LINGERING_SOUL_OBFUSCATE" />
			<div element="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_LINGERING_SOUL_XENOGLOSSIA" />
			<div element="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_LINGERING_SOUL_SUPERNAL_BODY" />
			<div element="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_LINGERING_SOUL_PIERCING_CHILL" />
			<div element="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_LINGERING_SOUL_GHASTLY_VISAGE" />
			<div element="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_LINGERING_SOUL_ETERNAL_SPIRIT" />
			<div element="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_LINGERING_SOUL_POSSESSION_MASTERY" />
			<div element="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_LINGERING_SOUL_RAVAGE_SOUL" />
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="short">A ghostly character with unfinished business.</set>
            <set name="hd">d6</set>
            <set name="sourceUrl">https://img.fireden.net/tg/image/1511/28/1511285281092.pdf</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false"/>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CONSTITUTION"/>
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Lingering Soul)" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INVESTIGATION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_RELIGION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SLIGHTOFHAND|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_STEALTH" number="3"/>
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_LINGERING_SOUL_SPIRIT_BINDING" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_LINGERING_SOUL_PHANTOM_CALLING" level="1" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_LINGERING_SOUL_GHOSTLY_FORM" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_LINGERING_SOUL_POSSESSION" level="2" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_LINGERING_SOUL_CONSUME_ENCHANTMENT" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_ABILITYSCOREIMPROVEMENT_LINGERINGSPIRIT" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_LINGERING_SOUL_PREVADE_THE_FALLEN" level="5" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_LINGERING_SOUL_UNSEEN_PASSENGER" level="5" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_LINGERING_SOUL_OBFUSCATE" level="7" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_LINGERING_SOUL_XENOGLOSSIA" level="9" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_LINGERING_SOUL_SUPERNAL_BODY" level="10" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_LINGERING_SOUL_PIERCING_CHILL" level="13" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_LINGERING_SOUL_GHASTLY_VISAGE" level="14" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_LINGERING_SOUL_ETERNAL_SPIRIT" level="17" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_LINGERING_SOUL_POSSESSION_MASTERY" level="18" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_LINGERING_SOUL_RAVAGE_SOUL" level="20" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Spirit Binding" type="Class Feature" source="Ryan" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_LINGERING_SOUL_SPIRIT_BINDING">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 1st level, you must select an object or creature of your choice (it could be an heirloom, weapon, or al ly) to bind to indefinitely. You must remain within 150 feet of your bound target at a ll times, and if the object or creature leaves your 150 foot radius, you are dragged along with it. You are always aware of where your bound object or creature is in relation to you.</p>
            <p class="indent">Should the object be destroyed, or the creature s lain, you immediately drop to 0 hit points. If you regain consciousness without a spirit bond, you must immediate ly select a new object or creature within 150 feet to bind to. If nothing is present to bind to, you are paralyzed until an object or creature comes within 150 feet for you to bind to.</p>
			</description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You are bound to an object or creature and must remain within 150 feet of it at all times. If the object or creature leaves your 150 foot radius, you are dragged along with it. You are always aware of where your bound object or creature is in relation to you. If the object is destroyed or the creature slain, you immediately drop to 0 hit points. If you regain conciousness without a spirit bond, you must immediately select a new object or creature within 150 feet to bind to.</description>   
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Phantom Calling" type="Class Feature" source="Ryan" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_LINGERING_SOUL_PHANTOM_CALLING">
        <description>
            <p>Beginning at 1st level, you select a Phantom Calling that defines the path of your spiritual journey. Choose Poltergeist, Wraith, or Spirit Guardian, all detailed at the end of the class description. The calling you choose grants you features at 1st level and again at 6th, 11th, and 15th level.</p>
			<p class="indent">The Phantom Calling you select will define one of your Ability Scores to carry over from life as the characteristic that now defines you in undeath, called your Aspect. The ability modifier from this ability score also acts as your Aspect modifier in regards to Lingering Soul features.</p>
			<p class="indent">Some of your Lingering Soul features require you to make an Aspect attack, or your target to make a saving throw to resist a feature's effects. The modifier and saving throw DC is calculated as follows:</p>
			<center>
				<p><strong>Spell save DC</strong> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Aspect modifier</p>
				<p><strong>Spell attack modifier</strong> = your proficiency bonus + your Aspect modifier</p>
			</center>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <select type="Archetype" name="Phantom Calling" supports="Phantom Calling" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Ghostly Form" type="Class Feature" source="Ryan" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_LINGERING_SOUL_GHOSTLY_FORM">
        <description>
            <p>At 1st level, your physical body is no more, your new, spectral form existing in the space between realms. You gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>
					Your creature type is Undead, and you are considered undead in respect to all spells, abilities, and effects.
				</li>
				<li>
					You give off a cold glow equal to dim light for a 5 foot radius.
				</li>
				<li>
					You cannot physically carry any objects or wear equipment. You also no longer need to eat or drink, nor gain the benefits of any objects or substances that require ingestion.
				</li>
				<li>
					While you are not possessing a creature, you have damage resistance against bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from nonmagical weapons.
				</li>
				<li>
					You are immune to poison damage and the <i>poisoned</i> condition.
				</li>
				<li>
					You are immune to the <i>prone</i>, <i>grappled</i>, <i>restrained</i>, and <i>petrified</i> conditions.
				</li>
				<li>
					You can move through other creatures and objects as if they were difficult terrain. You take ldlO force damage if you end your turn inside an object.
				</li>
				<li>
					You fall at a rate of 60 feet per round, and do not suffer falling damage.
				</li>
				<li>
					You still take short or long rests per usual to use hit dice and regain the use of abilities, but do not require sleep.
				</li>
				<li>
					Should you fall to 0 hit points, you begin fading. You are considered unconscious, and make death saving throws as normal. Should you fail three death saving throws, your spirit withers away into the ether. Your soul is cast into the vaults of the underworld and cannot be recovered or resurrected outside of the use of a Wish spell.
				</li>
				<li>
					Should you ever be brought back to life via a spell or resurrection effect, you immediately lose all levels in Lingering Soul and return to life as your previous, living self. You gain back class levels in your original classes as they were upon death, plus one additional character level per level of Lingering Soul gained while playing as a spirit.
				</li>
			</ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
			<p>Your creature type is Undead and you are incabable of eating, drinking, carrying, or wearing any object. You give off a cold glow of dim light in a 5 foot radius. You are immune to poison damage and the poisoned condition. You are resistant to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from nonmagical weapons. You are immune to being prone, grappled, restrained, or petrified. You fall at a rate of 60 feet per round and do not suffer falling damage. You can move though other creatures and objects as if they were difficult terrain, but take 1d10 force damage if you end your turn inside an object.</p>
		</sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Possession" type="Class Feature" source="Ryan" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_LINGERING_SOUL_POSSESSION">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 2nd level, you discover the ability to enter the bodies of other creatures and influence their actions. As a bonus action, you can attempt to possess one creature within 5 feet of you. The creature must succeed on a Charisma saving throw or become possessed. A creature can fail this saving throw voluntarily.</p>
            <p class="indent">While possessing a creature, your body occupies the same space as the host and is not visible. You cannot be targeted or affected by any attacks or spells, but you suffer damage equal to half of any damage dealt to the host while possessed. If the host moves, you move with them. You can only experience what the host sees and hears, and can communicate with them telepathically. You can only use features that specify their use while possessing a host.</p> 
            <p class="indent">A possessed creature acts as normal on its turn. However, you can use your action to force the possessed creature to make an immediate weapon attack against a target of your choice within range, adding your Aspect modifier to the damage dealt. You can instead use your action to force the possessed creature to Dash in a direction of your choice, or take the Dodge action.</p>
			<p class="indent">This possession lasts until the host drops to 0 hit points, you drop to 0 hit points, or you are forced out by an effect like the <i>dispel evil and good</i> spell or <i>turn undead</i> ability. You then reappear in an unoccupied space within 5 feet of the creature. You can choose to end your possession for free at the start of your turn. The host creature is immune to your possession for 24 hours after succeeding on the possession saving throw or after the possession ends (unless the creature wishes otherwise).</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You gain the ability to possess another creature as a bonus action. They get to make a Charisma saving throw vs DC {{soul:dc}}, though they can voluntarily fail it. You move with the host and take half the damage it does. You can use your action to have the creature make a melee attack or take the dodge or dash action.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
	<element name="Consume Enchantment" type="Class Feature" source="Ryan" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_LINGERING_SOUL_CONSUME_ENCHANTMENT">
        <description>
            <p>At 3rd level, you have learned how to absorb powerful arcane enchantments from potent items. You can spend an hour syphoning the mystic properties of a magical item. When the hour ritual is complete, the enchantment (and any attunement) becomes indefinitely bound to your ghostly form, leaving the item inert. You have a limit of five enchantments that can be bound to you in this way, of which three can be enchantments that require attunement (the process attunes it to you). To consume a new enchantment beyond five, you must permanently discard an existing enchantment you harbor.</p>
            <p class="indent">A weapon enchantment you have consumed can be applied to any physical or weapon attack you make. If you are possessing a host, you can apply one of your consumed weapon enchantments to any attacks you force them to make with a non-magical weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent">Some items and artifacts cannot be consumed in this way (DM's discretion).</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You gain the ability to consume enchantments off of magical items. You destroy the item but gain the benefit permanently. You can only have 5 consumed items and 3 attunements at one time.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="Ryan" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_ABILITYSCOREIMPROVEMENT_LINGERINGSPIRIT">
		<compendium display="false" />
        <description>
            <p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Lingering Soul 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Lingering Soul,4" level="4" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Lingering Soul 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Lingering Soul,8" level="8" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Lingering Soul 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Lingering Soul,12" level="12" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Lingering Soul 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Lingering Soul,16" level="16" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Lingering Soul 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Lingering Soul,19" level="19" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Prevade the Fallen" type="Class Feature" source="Ryan" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_LINGERING_SOUL_PREVADE_THE_FALLEN">
        <description>
            <p>At 5th level, you've become adept enough at possession to utilize the shell of a slain creature as a vessel. Your Possession ability can now target the dead body of a creature within 5 feet of you, and the corpse automatically fails their saving throw. This possession ends after 1 minute. The host corpse is considered to have 1 hit point and starts prone. You can use your movement to move the host corpse at your speed. If a host corpse is reduced to 0 hit points, or the possession ends, it is destroyed and cannot be possessed again.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You gain the ability to possess a slain creature for 1 minute. The creature is considered to have 1 hit point. </description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Unseen Passenger" type="Class Feature" source="Ryan" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_LINGERING_SOUL_UNSEEN_PASSENGER">
        <description>
            <p>At 5th level, you've become more adept at controlling and manipulating the bodies of your host. If a creature is unaware of your presence, you can attempt to possess them without them knowing. Make a Dexterity (Stealth) check contested by the target's Wisdom (Perception) check. If you win, and they fail their saving throw, you successfully possess them without their knowledge.</p>
			<p class="indent">Whenever you force the host to do anything, they can make a Wisdom (Insight) check against your Lingering Soul DC. On a success, they become aware of the possession.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can attempt to possess a creature that is not aware of your presence. You make a Dexterity (Stealth) check contested by the target's Wisdom (Perception) check to do so. Whenever you force the host to do something they can make a Wisdom (Insight) check against DC {{soul:dc}} to become aware of the possession.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Obfuscate" type="Class Feature" source="Ryan" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_LINGERING_SOUL_OBFUSCATE">
        <description>
            <p>Beginning at 7th level, you can temporarily become incorporeal to avoid the brunt of an attack against you. When an attacker that you can see hits you with an attack, you can use your reaction to halve the attack's damage against you.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you would receive half of the damage a possessed creature suffers from an attack, you can use your reaction to reduce it to a quarter of the damage suffered.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When an attacker you can see hits you or your host with an attack, you can use your reaction to halve the attack's damage against you.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Xenoglossia" type="Class Feature" source="Ryan" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_LINGERING_SOUL_XENOGLOSSIA">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 9th level, you can use an action while possessing a host to manipulate their speech and force them to say or yell a short phrase of twenty-tlve words or less. Any Charisma ability checks initiated this way use your Charisma score and skills in place of the host's.</p>
			<p class="indent">If the host begins casting a spell that uses verbal components, you can use your reaction to try to force them to fumble the incantation. The host must make a Constitution saving throw against your Lingering Soul DC. On a failure, the spell fai ls, the spell slot is expended, and the possession immediately ends.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can use an action to force your host to say or yell a short phrase. If the host is casting a spell that uses verbal components, you can use your reaction to make a Constitution saving throw against DC {{soul:dc}} or the spell is interupted. If you succeed in countering a spell in this way, your possession immediately ends.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Supernal Body" type="Class Feature" source="Ryan" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_LINGERING_SOUL_SUPERNAL_BODY">
        <description>
            <p>Upon reaching lOth level, you've further expanded the capabilities of your ghostly body. You gain the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>
					You gain a fly speed equal to your speed.
				</li>
				<li>
					You can cast <i>invisibility</i> on yourself, without requiring material components, twice per day.
				</li>
			</ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You gain a fly speed equal to your speed and can cast invisivility twice per day without material components.</description>
        </sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="speed:fly" value="speed" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Piercing Chill" type="Class Feature" source="Ryan" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_LINGERING_SOUL_PIERCING_CHILL">
        <description>
            <p>At 13th level, you have learned to expand your ghostly chill to temporarily freeze your host's vitals. When a possessed host makes an attack, you can use your reaction to give the triggering attack disadvantage.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can use your reaction to give your host disadvantage on one attack.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
	<element name="Ghastly Visage" type="Class Feature" source="Ryan" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_LINGERING_SOUL_GHASTLY_VISAGE">
        <description>
            <p>Beginning at 14th level, you can twist your appearance into a terrifying vision of undeath. As an action, choose any number of creatures within 30 feet of you. If they can see you, they must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be frightened of you until the end of your next turn. On subsequent turns, you can use your action to extend the duration of this effect on the frightened creatures until the end of your next turn. This effect ends if a creature ends its turn out of line of sight of you.</p>
			<p class="indent">If a creature succeeds on its saving throw, you can't use this feature on that creature again for 24 hours.</p>
			<p class="indent">You must finish a short or long rest before you can use this feature again.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>As an action you can choose any number of creatures within 30 feet to make a Wisdom saving throw vs DC {{soul:dc}} or become frightened of you until the end of your next turn. You can continue to use your action on subsequent turns to maintain the frighten.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
	<element name="Eternal Spirit" type="Class Feature" source="Ryan" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_LINGERING_SOUL_ETERNAL_SPIRIT">
        <description>
            <p>Upon reaching 17th level, your s pirit body has evolved to become tethered to this plane, never truly destroyed by unhallowed weapons. You are no longer bound to an object or creature, as per your Spirit Binding feature, and may wander as you please.</p>
			<p class="indent">Whenever you would be destroyed by failing a third death saving throw, you instead vanish for 24 hours, slumbering on the Ethereal Plane. You then return at the spot where you fell, rested as if you completed a long rest. You suffer a -4 penalty to all attack rolls, saving throws, and ability checks. Every time you finish a subsequent long rest, the penalty is reduced by 1 until it disappears.</p>
			<p class="indent">If the area where your s pirit was s truck down is under the e ffect of a Hallow spell when you return, your spirit is instead scattered and lost forever in the Ethereal Plane.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You are no longer bound to an object or creature and may wander as you please. Whenever you would die, you instead slumber on the Ethereal Plane for 24 hours, coming back with a -4 penalty to attack rolls, saving throws, and ability checks. This penalty is reduced by 1 every time you finish a long rest.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
	<element name="Possession Mastery" type="Class Feature" source="Ryan" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_LINGERING_SOUL_POSSESSION_MASTERY">
        <description>
            <p>At 18th level. you have gained the ability to completely control a host. While possessing a living host. you can use your action to take total and precise control of the target. Until the end of your next turn, the creature takes only the actions you choose. and doesn't do anything that you don't allow it to do. During this time, you can also cause the creature to use a reaction, but this requires you to use your own reaction as well.</p>
			<p class="indent">Each time the host takes damage during a turn where you are controlling it this way, it makes a new Charisma saving throw against your possession. If the saving throw succeeds, the possession ends.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can use your action to take complete control of your host for 1 turn. The creature takes only the actions you choose and you can use your reaction to use the creature's reaction. Each time the host takes damage during this time, it gets a Charisma saving throw vs DC {{soul:dc}} or the possession ends.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
	<element name="Ravage Soul" type="Class Feature" source="Ryan" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_LINGERING_SOUL_RAVAGE_SOUL">
        <description>
            <p>When you reach 20th level, you can try to sunder the spirit of a host from its body. While possessing a host that is neither undead nor a construct, you can use your action to end the possession and force the creature to make a Constitution saving throw. It takes 12dl0 necrotic damage on a failure, and half as much damage on a success. If the creature is brought to under 50 hit points by this damage, it dies.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you must finish a short or long rest before you can use it again.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Once per short or long rest you may use your action to force your host to make a Constitustion saving throw vs DC {{soul:dc}}. On a failure they take 12d10 damage, half as much on a success. If this damage brings the target below 50 hit points, it dies.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
	
    <!-- Poltergeist -->
    <element name="Calling of the Poltergeist" type="Archetype" source="Ryan" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_LINGERING_SOUL_CALLING_OF_THE_POLTERGEIST">
        <supports>Phantom Calling</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Those souls who wish to s till cxcr'ltheir will on the physical world, shifting steel and flesh with their anger alone, begin walking the way of the Poltergeist. Abandoning s ubtlety to instead harness a maelstrom of unbridled emotion, the Poltergeist exhibits the ability to lift. push, and manipulate the substantial realm around them. The clattering of dangerous weapons and helpless attackers being invis ibly flung through the air mercilessly marks the fury of these ferocious shades.</p>
			<p class="indent">Upon becoming a Poltergeist, choose either your Strength, Dexterity or Intelligence to become your Aspect. Your Aspect modifier is equal to that of the chosen Ability Score. You gain proficiency in Strength saving throws.</p>
            <div element="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_POLTERGEIST_IMPLEMENTS_OF_ANGER" />
            <div element="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_POLTERGEIST_HAUNT" />
            <div element="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_POLTERGEIST_SPECTRAL_WARRIOR" />
            <div element="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_POLTERGEIST_PHANTASMIC_FORCE" />
            <div element="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_POLTERGEIST_TORRENT_OF_RAGE" />
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="sourceUrl">https://img.fireden.net/tg/image/1511/28/1511285281092.pdf</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description>Test, where does this show up????</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_STRENGTH"/>
			<select type="Archetype Feature" name="Aspect Ability Score" supports="Poltergeist Aspect" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_POLTERGEIST_IMPLEMENTS_OF_ANGER" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_POLTERGEIST_HAUNT" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_POLTERGEIST_SPECTRAL_WARRIOR" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_POLTERGEIST_PHANTASMIC_FORCE" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_POLTERGEIST_TORRENT_OF_RAGE" level="15" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Implements of Anger" type="Archetype Feature" source="Ryan" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_POLTERGEIST_IMPLEMENTS_OF_ANGER">
        <description>
            <p>Upon choosing to become a Poltergeist at 1st level, you gain proficiency with 3 melee weapons of your choice.</p>
            <p class="indent">You may choose 2 additional melee weapons to gain proficiency with at 6th level, 11th level, and 15th level.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You gain proficiency with 3 melee weapons.</description>
            <description level="6">You gain proficiency with 5 melee weapons.</description>
			<description level="11">You gain proficiency with 7 melee weapons.</description>
			<description level="15">You gain proficiency with 9 melee weapons.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Haunt" type="Archetype Feature" source="Ryan" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_POLTERGEIST_HAUNT">
        <description>
            <p>Beginning at 1st level, you are able to focus on small objects and move them with a larming speed using your phantom strength. You learn the Mage Hand cantrip.</p>
            <p class="indent">As an action. you can choose an object that weighs no more than 10 pounds within 30 feet of you. You mystically hurl it 30 feet in any direction. If you choose to have the object strike a creature, roll a ranged Aspect attack against that creature. On a hit, the target takes ld4 + your Aspect modifier bludgeoning damage, and the object drops to the ground. If the object is a weapon you are prof1eicnt in, use the weapon's damage dice and type instead. Any magical weapons you are proficient with and attuned to can be used with this feature.</p>
			<p class="indent">If the target object is currently held by another creature, they must make a Stre ngth saving throw. On a fa iled save. the creature drops the object you choose and you may move it 15 feet with this feature.</p>
			<p class="indent">Upon reaching 6th level, you can target and move two objects when you take the Haunt action instead of one. Alternatively, you can move a single object twice in rapid succession, allowing two attacks with a single weapon or object.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You have learned the Mage Hand cantrip. In addition, as an action, you can choose an object weighing 10 pounds or less and hurl it 30 feet. You can attempt to hit another creature by making a ranged Aspect attack against the creature. On a hit, the target taked 1d4 + {{soul:mod}} buldgeoning damage. If the object is a weapon you are proficient with, use the weapons damage die and type. This can be used on object held by another creature, but they get a Strength saving throw DC {{soul:dc}}. If they fail, the object can be moved 15 feet away from them.</description>
			<description level="6">You have learned the Mage Hand cantrip. In addition, as an action, you can choose 2 objects weighing 10 pounds or less and hurl them 30 feet. You can also choose to move a single object twice. You can attempt to hit another creature by making a ranged Aspect attack against the creature. On a hit, the target taked 1d4 + {{soul:mod}} buldgeoning damage. If the object is a weapon you are proficient with, use the weapons damage die and type. This can be used on object held by another creature, but they get a Strength saving throw DC {{soul:dc}}. If they fail, the object can be moved 15 feet away from them.</description>
        </sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGE_HAND" />
		</rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Spectral Warrior" type="Archetype Feature" source="Ryan" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_POLTERGEIST_SPECTRAL_WARRIOR">
        <description>
            <p>When you reach 6th level, you can will nearby gear to surround your spectral body. As a bonus action, select any pieces of wearable equipment within 30 feet that aren't currently being worn by a creature. The equipment is drawn into the air and assembles around you, bestowing you with any Armor Class bonuses, benefits, and detriments granted by wearing the equipment. You need not be proficient with any armor to wear it in this way, and you ignore the Strength requirement of heavy armor. Any magical equipment you are attuned to can be used with this feature. You are still limited by equipment slots (one helmet, one set of boots. etc).</p> 
            <p class="indent">This equipment remains assembled around you until you choose to drop it, you attempt to possess a creature, you pass through a solid creature or object. or until you take a short or long rest. Equipment dropped is immediately left on the ground in your space.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>As a bonus action you can cause armor within 30 feet of you to assemble around you, confering any benefits and detriments to you.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Phantasmic Force" type="Archetype Feature" source="Ryan" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_POLTERGEIST_PHANTASMIC_FORCE">
        <description>
            <p>Upon reaching 11th level, you can exert your ghostly will to manipulate living creatures from a distance. As an action, you can choose a creature that is large or smaller within 30 feet of you. The target must make a Strength saving throw or be hurled 30 feet in any direction, including upward. If the target comes into contact with a hard surface, creature, or heavy object, the target takes 1d8 bludgeoning damage per 10 feet moved and is knocked prone.</p>
			<p class="indent">If the target creature is hurled into a second creature within range, the second creature must make a Dexterity saving throw. The second creature also takes 1d8 bludgeoning damage per 10 feet moved and is knocked prone on a fai led save, or half as much damage and is not knocked prone on a s uccessful one.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Aspect modiAer (minimum of once). You regain any expended uses when you finish a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>As an action, Aspect modifier ({{soul:mod}}) times per short or long rest, you can hurl a creature 30 feet in any direction. They get a Strength saving throw, DC {{soul:dc}}, to resist this effect. If they come in contact with a hard surface or another creature the target taked 1d8 bludgeoning damage per 10 feet moved and is knocked prone. If it is hurled into another creature, the second creature gets a Dexterity saving throw or takes the same damage and is knocked prone. On a successful save, the second target only takes half damage and is not knocked prone.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Torrent of Rage" type="Archetype Feature" source="Ryan" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_POLTERGEIST_TORRENT_OF_RAGE">
        <description>
            <p>Once you reach 1St h level, you·ve learned to unleash your spectral anger. As an act ion, you begin ca lling surrounding debris to spiral and orbit you at incredible speeds. Whenever an enemy crea ture comes within 30 feet of you for the first time on a turn, or starts its turn within 30 feet of you, it immediately suffers 1 d6 slashing damage, 1 d6 piercing damage, and I d6 bludgeoning damage. This feature lasts for up to I minute.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you must finish a long rest before you can usc it again.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Once per long rest you can, as an action, surround yourself with debris that orbits at incredible speeds. Whenever an enemy creature comes within 30 feet of you for the first time on a turn, or starts it's turn within 30 feet of you, it immediately suffers 1d6 slashing, 1d6 piercing, and 1d6 bludgeoning damage. This ability lasts for 1 minute.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
	<element name="Aspect of Strength" type="Archetype Feature" source="Ryan" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_POLTERGEIST_ASPECT_OF_STRENGTH">
		<supports>Poltergeist Aspect</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Strength becomes your Aspect Ability Score, which affects all of your Save DCs.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<stat name="soul:mod" value="strength:modifier" />
			<stat name="soul:dc" value="8" />
			<stat name="soul:dc" value="proficiency" />
			<stat name="soul:dc" value="strength:modifier" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Aspect of Dexterity" type="Archetype Feature" source="Ryan" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_POLTERGEIST_ASPECT_OF_DEXTERITY">
		<supports>Poltergeist Aspect</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Dexterity becomes your Aspect Ability Score, which affects all of your Save DCs.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<stat name="soul:mod" value="dexterity:modifier" />
			<stat name="soul:dc" value="8" />
			<stat name="soul:dc" value="proficiency" />
			<stat name="soul:dc" value="dexterity:modifier" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Aspect of Intelligence" type="Archetype Feature" source="Ryan" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_POLTERGEIST_ASPECT_OF_INTELLIGENCE">
		<supports>Poltergeist Aspect</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Intelligence becomes your Aspect Ability Score, which affects all of your Save DCs.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<stat name="soul:mod" value="intelligence:modifier" />
			<stat name="soul:dc" value="8" />
			<stat name="soul:dc" value="proficiency" />
			<stat name="soul:dc" value="intelligence:modifier" />
		</rules>
	</element>
    <!-- /Poltergeist -->
	
	<!-- Wraith -->
    <element name="Calling of the Wraith" type="Archetype" source="Ryan" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_LINGERING_SOUL_CALLING_OF_THE_WRAITH">
        <supports>Phantom Calling</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The Wraith is a dangerous path for any soul to take, and few have a choice should their life been entwined with dubious arcane pursuits or necromantic corruption. Those who take the path of the wraith embrace the desire for warmth and the hunger for the life they once had. Their energy becomes dark, ens hrouded in shadow and malice... but the will remains, and there are tales of those lost souls who could master the craving and focus their hate on those who deserve it.</p>
			<p class="indent">Upon becoming a wraith, choose either your Dexterity, Intelligence, or Charisma to become your Aspect. Your Aspect modifier is equal to that of the chosen Ability Score. You gain proficiency in Intelligence saving throws.</p>
            <div element="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_POLTERGEIST_SCYTHING_CLAW" />
            <div element="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_POLTERGEIST_SHADOW_OF_THE_GRAVE" />
            <div element="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_POLTERGEIST_AURA_OF_MIDNIGHT" />
            <div element="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_POLTERGEIST_CREATE_SPECTER" />
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="sourceUrl">https://img.fireden.net/tg/image/1511/28/1511285281092.pdf</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description>Test, where does this show up????</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_INTELLIGENCE"/>
			<select type="Archetype Feature" name="Aspect Ability Score" supports="Wraith Aspect" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_POLTERGEIST_SCYTHING_CLAW" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_POLTERGEIST_SHADOW_OF_THE_GRAVE" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_POLTERGEIST_AURA_OF_MIDNIGHT" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_POLTERGEIST_CREATE_SPECTER" level="15" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Scything Claw" type="Archetype Feature" source="Ryan" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_POLTERGEIST_SCYTHING_CLAW">
        <description>
            <p>Upon following this calling at 1st level, you gain the ability to tear through creatures with ghastly claws, stealing some of their essence. As an action, you can make a melee Aspect attack against a creature within 5 feet of you. On a hit, the target takes necrotic damage equal to 1d8 + your Aspect modifier. If the target isn't undead or a construct, you regain hit points equal to half of the damage dealt.</p>
            <p class="indent">The damage of your Scything Claw increases to 2d8 at 6th level, 3d8 at 11th level, and 4d8 at 15th level.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>As an action you can make a melee Aspect attack against a creature within 5 feet of you. It does 1d8 + {{soul:mod}} necrotic damage. If the target is not undead or a construct, you regain hit points equal to half the damage dealt.</description>
            <description level="6">As an action you can make a melee Aspect attack against a creature within 5 feet of you. It does 2d8 + {{soul:mod}} necrotic damage. If the target is not undead or a construct, you regain hit points equal to half the damage dealt.</description>
			<description level="11">As an action you can make a melee Aspect attack against a creature within 5 feet of you. It does 3d8 + {{soul:mod}} necrotic damage. If the target is not undead or a construct, you regain hit points equal to half the damage dealt.</description>
			<description level="15">As an action you can make a melee Aspect attack against a creature within 5 feet of you. It does 4d8 + {{soul:mod}} necrotic damage. If the target is not undead or a construct, you regain hit points equal to half the damage dealt.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Shadow of the Grave" type="Archetype Feature" source="Ryan" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_POLTERGEIST_SHADOW_OF_THE_GRAVE">
        <description>
            <p>At 6th level, your spectral body becomes further attuned to the cold, dark world of the undead. Your ghostly form no longer emits a cold, dim light out in a 5 foot radius. You gain darkvision out to 60 feet, as well as resistance to cold and necrotic damage, but also have disadvantage on attack rolls and Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight while in direct sunlight.</p>
			<p class="indent">While possessing a host, you can choose to impart them with the benefits of this feature, but in doing so also impart the penalties while in direct sunlight.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You no longer emit light in a 5 foot radius around yourself and gain darkvision out to 60 feet. You also gain resistance to cold and necrotic damage, but you have disadvantage on attack rolls and Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight while in direct sunlight. You may impart both the benefits and penalties upon your host if you desire.</description>
        </sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_DARKVISION" />
		</rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Aura of Midnight" type="Archetype Feature" source="Ryan" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_POLTERGEIST_AURA_OF_MIDNIGHT">
        <description>
            <p>Beginning at 11th level, your presence devours nearby light, obscuring your form while syphoning life lost under darkness. Your icy presence extinguishes any natural open flame within 30 feet of you. While in dim light or darkness, you can take the Hide action as a bonus action. Whenever a living creature in dim light or darkness dies within 30 feet of you, you gain temporary hit points equal to 1d8 + your Aspect modifier. This aura remains while possessing a host.</p> 
            <p class="indent">At 15th level, the amount of temporary hit points gained increases to 2d8 +your Aspect modifier.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Any natural open flames within 30 feet of you are extinguished. While in dim ligth or darkness you can take the Hide action as a bonus action. Whenever a living creature in dim light or darkenss dies within 30 feet of you, you gain temporary hit points equal to 1d8 + {{soul:mod}}.</description>
			<description level="15">Any natural open flames within 30 feet of you are extinguished. While in dim ligth or darkness you can take the Hide action as a bonus action. Whenever a living creature in dim light or darkenss dies within 30 feet of you, you gain temporary hit points equal to 2d8 + {{soul:mod}}.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Create Specter" type="Archetype Feature" source="Ryan" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_POLTERGEIST_CREATE_SPECTER">
        <description>
            <p>Upon reaching 15th level, you've learned how to spread the curse of undeath to your fallen foes. As an action, you can target a humanoid corpse within 10 feet that has been dead for no longer than 1 minute, and died violently. The target's spirit rises as a specter in the space of the corpse or in the nearest unoccupied space. The specter is under your control, allowing you to issue commands to the creature while you are conscious (no action required), which it does its best to obey. You can specify a simple and general course of the action, such as 'Attack that creature", "Run over there", or "fetch that object." If the creature completed the order and doesn't receive further direction from you, it defends and preserves itself and you to the best of its ability. You can have no more than a number of specters equal to your Aspect modifier under your control at one time.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>As an action you can target a humanoid corpse within 10 feet that has been dead less than a minute, and died violently. You create a specter in that space under your control. You can have {{soul:mod}} specters under your control at one time.</description>
        </sheet>
	</element>
    <element name="Aspect of Dexterity" type="Archetype Feature" source="Ryan" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WRAITH_ASPECT_OF_DEXTERITY">
		<supports>Wraith Aspect</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Dexterity becomes your Aspect Ability Score, which affects all of your Save DCs.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<stat name="soul:mod" value="dexterity:modifier" />
			<stat name="soul:dc" value="8" />
			<stat name="soul:dc" value="proficiency" />
			<stat name="soul:dc" value="dexterity:modifier" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Aspect of Intelligence" type="Archetype Feature" source="Ryan" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WRAITH_ASPECT_OF_INTELLIGENCE">
		<supports>Wraith Aspect</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Intelligence becomes your Aspect Ability Score, which affects all of your Save DCs.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<stat name="soul:mod" value="intelligence:modifier" />
			<stat name="soul:dc" value="8" />
			<stat name="soul:dc" value="proficiency" />
			<stat name="soul:dc" value="intelligence:modifier" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Aspect of Charisma" type="Archetype Feature" source="Ryan" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WRAITH_ASPECT_OF_CHARISMA">
		<supports>Wraith Aspect</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Charisma becomes your Aspect Ability Score, which affects all of your Save DCs.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<stat name="soul:mod" value="charisma:modifier" />
			<stat name="soul:dc" value="8" />
			<stat name="soul:dc" value="proficiency" />
			<stat name="soul:dc" value="charisma:modifier" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<!-- /Wraith	-->
	
	<!-- Spirit Guardian -->
    <element name="Calling of the Spirit Guardian" type="Archetype" source="Ryan" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_LINGERING_SOUL_CALLING_OF_THE_SPIRIT_GUARDIAN">
        <supports>Phantom Calling</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Some souls that persist in the mortal realm seek a greater purpose. Whether they remain to see to some divine duty, or wish to entice and corrupt the souls of others in the name of a dark patron, it's these spirits who invite deific guidance into their fate that begin to resemble the celestial beings or twisted fiends they worship. Relying on physical vessels to channel their fury, these guardians use their gifts to protect, harm, or influence all they encounter.</p>
			<p class="indent">Upon becoming a spirit guardian, choose either your Wisdom or Charisma to become your Aspect. Your Aspect modifier is equal to that of the chosen Ability Score. You gain proficiency in Charisma saving throws.</p>
            <div element="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_GUARDIAN_INVOKE_SMITE" />
            <div element="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_GUARDIAN_SYMPATHETIC_MENDING" />
            <div element="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_GUARDIAN_DIVINE_BARRIER" />
            <div element="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_GUARDIAN_CONSECRATED_EMANATION" />
            <div element="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_GUARDIAN_SAVIOR_SPIRIT" />
			<div element="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_GUARDIAN_GUARDIAN_TRANSFORMATION" />
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="sourceUrl">https://img.fireden.net/tg/image/1511/28/1511285281092.pdf</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description>Test, where does this show up????</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CHARISMA"/>
			<select type="Archetype Feature" name="Aspect Ability Score" supports="Spirit Guardian Aspect" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_GUARDIAN_INVOKE_SMITE" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_GUARDIAN_SYMPATHETIC_MENDING" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_GUARDIAN_DIVINE_BARRIER" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_GUARDIAN_CONSECRATED_EMANATION" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_GUARDIAN_SAVIOR_SPIRIT" level="15" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_GUARDIAN_GUARDIAN_TRANSFORMATION" level="15" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Invoke Smite" type="Archetype Feature" source="Ryan" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_GUARDIAN_INVOKE_SMITE">
        <description>
            <p>When you choose this calling at 1st level, can instill power into the weapons of nearby creatures to strike with divine flame. As an action, target a weapon or object within 30 feet of you. Until the end of your next turn, the next time that weapon or object hits a creature, it deals an additional ld8 radiant damage (if you are good or neutral), or ld8 necrotic damage (if you are evil). You can use this feature while possessing a host.</p>
            <p class="indent">This damage increases by ld8 at 6th level, and again at 11th level and 15th level.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>As an action, you can add 1d8 Radiant or Necrotic damage to all strikes from a weapon or object until the end of you next turn.</description>
            <description>As an action, you can add 2d8 Radiant or Necrotic damage to all strikes from a weapon or object until the end of you next turn.</description>
			<description>As an action, you can add 3d8 Radiant or Necrotic damage to all strikes from a weapon or object until the end of you next turn.</description>
			<description>As an action, you can add 4d8 Radiant or Necrotic damage to all strikes from a weapon or object until the end of you next turn.</description>
        </sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Archetype Feature" name="Spirit Guardian Damage Type" supports="Spirit Guardian Damage" />
		</rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Sympathetic Mending" type="Archetype Feature" source="Ryan" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_GUARDIAN_SYMPATHETIC_MENDING">
        <description>
            <p>Beginning with this calling at lst level, you discover how to restore vitality through divine spiritual energy. As an action, target a creature within 30 feet of you to regain a number of hit points equal to ld8 + your Aspect modifier. You can use this feature while possessing a host, and if your host is not your target, your host also regains hit points equal to your Aspect modifier.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can use this feature twice. Upon reaching 6th level, the healing increases by 1d8 and you can use this feature three times. At llth level, the healing increases by 1d8 and you can use this feature four times. When you reach 15th level, the healing increases by ld8 and you can use this feature five times.</p>
			<p class="indent">You regain all uses of this feature after a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Twice per long rest, you can heal a target within 30 feet of you for 1d8 + {{soul:mod}}. If you target somebody besides your host, the host is healed for {{soul:mod}} hit points.</description>
			<description level="6">Three times per long rest, you can heal a target within 30 feet of you for 2d8 + {{soul:mod}}. If you target somebody besides your host, the host is healed for {{soul:mod}} hit points.</description>
			<description level="11">Four times per long rest, you can heal a target within 30 feet of you for 3d8 + {{soul:mod}}. If you target somebody besides your host, the host is healed for {{soul:mod}} hit points.</description>
			<description level="15">Five times per long rest, you can heal a target within 30 feet of you for 4d8 + {{soul:mod}}. If you target somebody besides your host, the host is healed for {{soul:mod}} hit points.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Divine Barrier" type="Archetype Feature" source="Ryan" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_GUARDIAN_DIVINE_BARRIER">
        <description>
            <p>At 6th level, you learn to protect your host by using your ghostly body to create a temporary shield. While you are possessing a host, if an attacker that you can see hits your host with an attack, you can use your reaction to grant your host a bonus to their AC or saving throw against the triggering attack equal to your Aspect modifier. Once the attack is resolved, the possession immediately ends, and you cannot use your Possession feature until the end of your next turn.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>As a reaction when your host gets hit with an attack, you can add {{soul:mod}} to either their AC or the saveing throw. Once the attack is resolved, the possession immediately ends, and you cannot use your Possession feature until the end of your next turn.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Consecrated Emanation" type="Archetype Feature" source="Ryan" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_GUARDIAN_CONSECRATED_EMANATION">
        <description>
            <p>Upon reaching 11th level, you can exude an aura that punishes those you deem unworthy. You can use an action to emit an aura around you up to a distance of 15 feet for up to 1 minute. You then designate any number of creatures you can see to be unaffected by it. An affected creature's speed is halved in the area, and when the creature enters the area for the first time on a turn or starts its turn there, it must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, the creature takes 3d6 radiant damage (if you are good or neutral), or 3d6 necrotic damage (if you are evil). On a successful save, the creature takes half as much damage. You can use this feature while possessing a host.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you must finish a short or long rest before you can use it again.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Once per short or long rest, as an action, you can emit an aura around you or your host out to a distance of 15 feet for 1 minute. Enemy creatures have their speed halved and when they enter the area for the first time on a turn or start thier turn there, it must make a Wisdom saving throw, DC {{soul:dc}}. On a failed save they take 3d6 Radiant or Necrotic damage. On a successful save they take half as much.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Savior Spirit" type="Archetype Feature" source="Ryan" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_GUARDIAN_SAVIOR_SPIRIT">
        <description>
            <p>When you reach 15th level, you radiate protective energy that staves off the shadow of death. All friendly creatures within 30 feet of you gain 1 hit point on a death saving throw roll of 18 to 20 on the d20. This aura remains while possessing a host.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Whenever a freindly creature within 30 feet of you rolls an 18 to 20 on a death saving throw, they regain 1 hit point.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
	<element name="Guardian Transformation" type="Archetype Feature" source="Ryan" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_GUARDIAN_GUARDIAN_TRANSFORMATION">
        <description>
            <p>At 15th level, you can use your action to temporarily imbue your host with some of your ghostly properties. For 10 minutes, your host gains the following features:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>
					They have damage resistance against bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from nonmagical weapons.
				</li>
				<li>
					They are immune to poison damage and the <i>poisoned</i> condition.
				</li>
				<li>
					They are immune to the <i>prone</i>, <i>grappled</i>, <i>restrained</i>, and <i>petrified</i> conditions.
				</li>
				<li>
					They can move through other creatures and objects as if they were difficult terrain. You both take 1d10 force damage if they end their turn inside an object.
				</li>
				<li>
					They have a fly speed equal to their speed.
				</li>
			</ul>
            <p class="indent">The duration ends prematurely if the possession ends. Once you use this feature, you must finish a long rest before you can use it again.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Once per long rest you can, as an action, imbue your host with some of your ghostly properties. For 10 minutes they have a fly speed equal to their walking speed and can move through creatures and objects as if they were difficult terrain. The have resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from nonmagical weapons. They are immune to poison damage and the poisoned condition. They are immune to the prone, grappled, restrained, and petrified conditions.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Aspect of Wisdom" type="Archetype Feature" source="Ryan" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_GUARDIAN_ASPECT_OF_WISDOM">
		<supports>Spirit Guardian Aspect</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Wisdom becomes your Aspect Ability Score, which affects all of your Save DCs.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<stat name="soul:mod" value="wisdom:modifier" />
			<stat name="soul:dc" value="8" />
			<stat name="soul:dc" value="proficiency" />
			<stat name="soul:dc" value="wisdom:modifier" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Aspect of Charisma" type="Archetype Feature" source="Ryan" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_GUARDIAN_ASPECT_OF_CHARISMA">
		<supports>Spirit Guardian Aspect</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Charisma becomes your Aspect Ability Score, which affects all of your Save DCs.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<stat name="soul:mod" value="charisma:modifier" />
			<stat name="soul:dc" value="8" />
			<stat name="soul:dc" value="proficiency" />
			<stat name="soul:dc" value="charisma:modifier" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Radiant Damage" type="Archetype Feature" source="Ryan" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_GUARDIAN_RADIANT_DAMAGE">
		<supports>Spirit Guardian Damage</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Your special damage type is Radiant damage.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<stat name="soul:damage" value="Radiant" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Necrotic Damage" type="Archetype Feature" source="Ryan" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_GUARDIAN_NECROTIC_DAMAGE">
		<supports>Spirit Guardian Damage</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Your special damage type is Necrotic damage.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<stat name="soul:damage" value="Necrotic" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<!-- /Spirit Guardian -->
</elements>
